	<string id="bar_ecolog_research_corrupted">
		<text>I, professor Kruglov, am deleting the results of our research for the sake of science and humanity as a whole. Dangerous knowledge must not pass into the hands of unreliable people who will seek to use it for the achievement of their criminal objectives. Those who read this note should know that our group was shot down above the Wild Territory by Mercs led by a notorious cutthroat called Wolfhound. By the time you read this we will probably be dead.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_ecolog_research_normal">
		<text>... as it turns out, the emissions affect primarily the advanced spheres of cognitive activity. Experiments show that only humans and animals with developed cognitive processes, such as dogs and horses are susceptible to these emissions. Of the above, only humans enter a state of trance - in animals the effect is limited to a strong feeling of fear. Judging by this evidence, it would be reasonable to conclude that the emissions are geared specifically towards the human brain. Extensive studies on "volunteers" have shown that subjects will leave the trance state if given medicamental treatment. We also developed experimental devices that will protect, to a certain extent, the human brain from these emissions. According to our calculations, the source of these emissions is located in the center of Lake Yantar. The source itself is likely to be artificial in nature, which means that it can be disabled. There is also the danger of criminals attempting to reach the source of the emissions and gaining control over it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_after_agroprom_documents_name">
		<text>Military documents</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_bar_darklab_documents_name">
		<text>Lab X18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_bar_x16_documents_name">
		<text>So the Brain Scorcher is man-made?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_darklab_documents_name">
		<text>Barkeep</text>
	</string>
	<string id="journal_before_radar_task_name">
		<text>After meeting with the Psycho</text>
	</string>
	<string id="rostok_tunel_gordon_diary">
		<text>12.01.2012 \n God damn my bosses...won't leave an old man alone. First Mesa, then some strange town in Russia. And now they send poor little Gordon into the endless Ukrainian plains. Take your jemmy and have fun. \n \n 20.03.2012 \n Made it into the Zone. Are there really no bears here? Who am I going to fight then? I'm not finding my bearings too well in this place. I had to give my little crowbar away for a can of meat. \n \n 26.04.2012 \n The blowout has started. The Barkeep told me to hide my ass and keep it hidden. I chased some rats out of an abandoned tunnel. I hope to wait out the bad weather in here.</text>
	</string>
