<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_0">
		<text>Thanks for your help, stalker! If you hadn't shown up, I'd be a dead man by now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_10001">
		<text>I am looking for information about Strelok, maybe you know something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_10002">
		<text>How do I get into the basement?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_15001">
		<text>Strelok's secret stash?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_15002">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_1501">
		<text>Yes, I heard about that. They even say he used to "work" in these parts and Strelok's stash is in the local basements. Rumor has it that his group's base was here too.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_1502">
		<text>This is one of the many exits which will lead you into the interconnected basements. Once you're in there, you're on your own - I don't have a map and the basement network is huge and confusing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_2">
		<text>I'm looking for info on Strelok. Seriy told me you know something about him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_30001">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_krot_start_3001">
		<text>Yeah, we looked for it too but couldn't find it. I'll send you some info about it. That's everything we have on the stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_stalker_about_0">
		<text>What's going on here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_stalker_about_1">
		<text>We're fighting, or more specifically, camping out like sitting ducks. Talk to Mole if you want to know more - he's the leader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_factory_stalker_start_0">
		<text>Man, that was a fight and a half - you wouldn't wish something like that on your worst enemy. Those army boys are getting pretty cocky!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_0">
		<text>Where is the Agroprom Research Institute?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_10">
		<text>Not far from here. Follow the road to the West and you'll come to the Institute's gates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_100">
		<text>I hear the military have set up a base there, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_120">
		<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_about_agroprom_20">
		<text>Yeah, there's a military base. I'm not sure how many of them there are exactly but it's at least a platoon. They're well-armed and you've got no chance of breaking through - they'll take you down before you can say "hello, comrades". The best way of getting in is during the night 'cause the base is well-guarded during the day - they got checkpoints everywhere and anyway, I heard a deserter-soldier from that base is hiding in the marshes. If you can find him I'm sure you can shake some useful info out of him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_0">
		<text>What's going on?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_100">
		<text>Me and my boys found a nice little area full of artifacts but those army bastards attacked us for some reason. I don't know what the hell they wanted from us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_200">
		<text>Yeah, I've heard about him. I think he used to "make his living" in this area - it's quite a good place, actually. He left a long time ago; I don't know when it was exactly and I've got no clue where he was headed. That's everything I can tell you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_2000">
		<text>You weren't waiting here for no reason, were you? Otherwise why would the Spetsnaz show up here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_250">
		<text>OK, I know something about Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_2500">
		<text>Yeah? I really need to know that!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_3500">
		<text>If you lied to me, I'll find you and finish what the soldiers couldn't!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_hasnot_met_seriy_400">
		<text>I'm not lying. I know that nobody trusts anyone here so you have little choice.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_100">
		<text>Seriy? Well, OK, listen. They say Strelok used to sneak around here. On top of that, his stash is somewhere around here below ground. I heard his group even has its base here. We also looked for the stash but we found jack shit. I'll give you the info about the stash, maybe you'll be luckier. This is everything we have on the stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_2000">
		<text>What else do you know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_actor_met_seriy_250">
		<text>I don't know anything else. I told you everything I knew and now you have to work it out on your own. Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_help_0">
		<text>Help me, stalker!!!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_krot_help_10">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_ratcatcher_start_0">
		<text>Don't shoot, man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_0">
		<text>What are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_20">
		<text>I'm coming back from the factory which is a bit further down the road. I don't know how but the army found out about our group. I didn't wait for them to show up and took off as quickly as I could. I hope our boys got out of there 'cause otherwise they won't be alive for much longer - you saw the choppers yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_300">
		<text>I see, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_esc_400">
		<text>I see, thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_0">
		<text>I've got a couple of questions.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_10">
		<text>What do you want to know?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_1000">
		<text>Anything interesting in the area?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_120">
		<text>How much do you need?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_130">
		<text>Here, take the money. Now tell me where it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_131">
		<text>Piss off!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_140">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_20">
		<text>Yeah, there are a couple of places but you'll have to share some of your wealth, buddy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_21">
		<text>It used to be pretty quiet but now the army has got all excited and started wasting everyone. They smoked the bandits out recently and I hear some managed to escape into the catacombs.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_30">
		<text>Thirty, deal?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_40">
		<text>The exit from the railway tunnel is nearby. It's fairly safe in the dead end. At least nobody has been eaten while sleeping...yet.  Also, to the Northwest of the factory you'll find a marsh with a wagon in it.  But be careful, there's a shitload of radiation around it, so it's best to approach it from the western side. Oh, and one more thing: a soldier has been spotted there. He's likely to be from the military base at the Institute. The poor bastard is probably crazy - he's been there for a couple of days and I doubt he'll survive much longer on his own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher_9999">
		<text>Bye!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_0">
		<text>Anything interesting happening here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_1">
		<text>Do you know about Ratcatcher? The info will cost you 30.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_11">
		<text>Deal.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_111">
		<text>We have a local hero around here called Ratcatcher. He lives in the marshes. The man bred so many rats in the collectors that they'll soon eat those army bastards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_1111">
		<text>Great. Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_1112">
		<text>Tell me more about the collectors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_11121">
		<text>Collectors are your standard shit-stinking sewers that take waste from the Institute and dumps it in the nearest water reservoir. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_111211">
		<text>Great. See you and take care of yourself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_12">
		<text>I know that already. Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_121">
		<text>I don't have anything else to tell you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_13">
		<text>I don't have enough cash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_14">
		<text>I'm not interested.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_3">
		<text>Anything interesting happening here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_31">
		<text>Nothing. Absolutely nothing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_about_ratcatcher1_311">
		<text>I see. Bye!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_0">
		<text>Tell me about this place.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_1">
		<text>This is the area around the Agroprom Research Institute. The Institute itself is to the Southwest. The factory, which served as the Institute's technical production facility, is to the North. The buildings have been abandoned for a long time and there's nothing to be found there, but the army has been searching there very actively recently.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_2">
		<text>Tell me more about the Institute.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_21">
		<text>There are loads of legends about the Institute. Before the accident in 1986 the only thing here was the Institute of Crop Selection and Genetics. The area where the factory is now was used for experimental crop fields. After the accident, they closed the Institute and burned the fields. Then they remembered about it, they whitewashes the building, put up a fence around it and built some barracks. I don't know what they did at the Institute but they didn't have any shortage of funding, that's for sure.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_3">
		<text>Tell me more about the factory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_31">
		<text>The factory was built at the end of the 80s. They said it was going to be used to build and test machines that could treat soil affected by radiation. As far as I know, nobody ever saw a single machine come out of that plant. It's totally empty now, which makes it a favorite spot for stalkers. I hear the place is pretty safe as long as you avoid the dark corners.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_stalker_talk_level_4">
		<text>Thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_0">
		<text>What are you doing?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_10">
		<text>I'm hiding here, I don't want no trouble.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_100">
		<text>Who are you hiding from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_120">
		<text>Catacombs?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_130">
		<text>Do you know where they keep documents at the Institute?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_140">
		<text>What are you going to do now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_141">
		<text>What are you going to do now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_20">
		<text>I am from the recon unit. They sent us into the catacombs to see what's going on below the base. It's hell down there, I'm telling you. I was the only one to get out of there... everyone else is probably dead by now. I don't want to go back to the base - those bastards are always using us to plug up all the holes in this damn Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_30">
		<text>Underground tunnels. They go from the Institute to the area around it - I'll show you the entrances. I don't have maps of the catacombs themselves.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_40">
		<text>At the HQ. It's on the third floor of the Institute. That's where they keep those damn papers. But it's a mission getting there. By day, the area is teaming with patrols but not as much at night. I'll tell you this for free: if you wanna get inside you'll have to go through the catacombs - you stand no chance at the gate.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks_50">
		<text>Hmm. I don't know. I am a deserter according to the military code and I need to get out of the Zone somehow. When we first got here there was a Zaporozhets in the garage that was almost working. I brought it back to life in half an hour but that damn captain took it for himself claiming he should have it according to the code. He drove it along this road and dumped it in the rain by the gate. If only I could get that car - making a run for it is much safer on wheels!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0">
		<text>Hello.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_01">
		<text>What's up?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_011">
		<text>Tell me about the collector. How do I get inside? Where are the exits and entrances?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0111">
		<text>It's dangerous inside the collector. There are six entrances and two of them are in the area around the Institute where the military have set up a base. That area is patrolled and the captain keeps the patrol schedule in his armory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_01111">
		<text>How do you know all that?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_011111">
		<text>The rats told me.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0111111">
		<text>I see. Bye! Good luck to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_012">
		<text>Nothing. See you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_013">
		<text>Who are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0134">
		<text>I live here, if you can call this a life. I breed rats in the collector to annoy the military at the Institute.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_0135">
		<text>I am Ratcatcher.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_01351">
		<text>What are you doing in this marsh?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="agr_swamp_ratcatcher_talks1_123">
		<text>Oh... I get it.... well, I'm from another story. Ha-ha-ha...</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
