	<string id="esc_direction_fire">
		<text>There will be no shooting unless I give the order. No itchy trigger fingers, understood?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_fanat_victory">
		<text>Victory!!! Everyone, get over here. Come, Marked One. We need to talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_return_dv">
		<text>Good, Marked One. Glad you're alive and decided to pay us a visit. Come over, and we'll have a chat. There's a little something coming up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_tutorial_end">
		<text>Excellent, your task is complete. Safe to say you've learned the basic skills.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="esc_wolf_thanks">
		<text>Marked One, the way to the camp is now open to you. Come over and we'll talk.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_fox_quest">
		<text>A word about Strelok, Marked One. A stalker just came back from a long raid. Fox he's called. Looks like he had a pretty rough time and he's asking for help. Some weird beasts followed him all the way back, he says he won't hold out much longer. I reckon the fella will know a bit about Strelok. Here are the coordinates. You might wanna hurry up though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_stalker_death">
		<text>Poor show, Marked One. The boys are dead, although that ain't exactly your fault. These things happen in the Zone. Anyway, you passed the test so get back here and we'll talk business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_stalker_helped">
		<text>Good job, Marked One. Keep it up and you'll make yourself a few friends. Pay me a visit and we'll talk business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_stalker_killed">
		<text>That wasn't very smart, Marked One. You passed the test but you're gonna have to deal with Wolf and his goons on your own now. Anyway, I'm waiting for you. We got more work to talk about.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="info_esc_give_agroprom_task">
		<text>Marked One, the military dug up some interesting stuff at the Agroprom Research Institute. I'd like to get my hands on it and you probably would too. Get the info and take it to the barman at the stalkers' bar. Now get moving!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_about_anomalies">
		<text>Watch out! You're right next to the anomalies. Use your bolts to work out their exact location and shape.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_about_pda">
		<text>Press Contact ($$ACTION_CONTACTS$$). People within 250 meters of you who have turned their PDAs will become visible in Contacts and on your visor Minimap. You will also see their attitude towards you, so you can look out for potential enemies. However, bandits and mutants (har har) don't usually turn their PDAs on, so be careful!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_map">
		<text>To activate the map, press '$$ACTION_MAP$$'.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_pda">
		<text>To activate the PDA, press '$$ACTION_ACTIVE_JOBS$$'.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_how_to_talk">
		<text>To talk to someone, aim at them and press '$$ACTION_USE$$'.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tips_esc_trader_quest_1">
		<text>Find the artifact in the area marked on the map and take it to the trader.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_flash_anomaly_alarm">
		<text>Pay attention, Marked One. Next time it could be you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_trader_give_medikit">
		<text>Give this moron a medkit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_trader_look_vagon">
		<text>Marked One! Forget the artifact, you'll drop it off later. Get to the trailer by the road ASAP. My boys need help there. The idiots opened fire at a passing chopper. I've sent you the coordinates.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="tutorial_trader_search_corpses">
		<text>Search the bodies - you might find something useful.</text>
	</string>
